<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Martijn van Vreeden</title>
    <link>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Martijn van Vreeden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to add Google Tag Manager to Hugo static website</title>
      <link>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/how-to-add-google-tag-manager-to-hugo-static-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/how-to-add-google-tag-manager-to-hugo-static-website/</guid>
      <description>How to add Google Tag Manager to a Hugo static websiteIn this article I will provide a step-by-step instruction and code samples on how to implement Google Tag Manager and a datalayer to your Hugo static website. As a digital analytics consultant I can appreciate the value a good Google Tag Manager (GTM) implementation can have for your business or even to optimize your user’s blog experience.
How to add the standard Google Tag Manager container to a Hugo websiteTo make sure that Google Tag Manager is enabled, we will have to include the Google Tag Manager container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo shortcode to serve images in next-gen formats</title>
      <link>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/hugo-shortcode-to-serve-images-in-next-gen-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/hugo-shortcode-to-serve-images-in-next-gen-formats/</guid>
      <description>Hugo shortcode to serve images in next-gen formatsIn my last blogpost I shared 10 ways to improve your Hugo website performance. My last tip was to serve images in next-gen formats. This could improve the performance of your website significantly. Eventhough there are multiple next-gen formats you can integrate, the best browser compatibility will come by using WebP, created by Google. Unfortunately, not all browsers support this format yet (looking at you, Safari!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways to improve your (Hugo) website performance</title>
      <link>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/10-ways-to-improve-your-hugo-website-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/10-ways-to-improve-your-hugo-website-performance/</guid>
      <description>10 Ways to improve your (Hugo) website performanceWebsite performance matters. Even if I would selfishly ignore all other human visitors to my website, I would be supporting Google’s mission to make the web faster and help myself climb the ranks of Google. In this article I describe 10 ways to make your Hugo website (or any other website) faster and give users a better experience.
These are the 10 tips I will be discussing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Youtube Shortcode for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/optimizing-the-youtube-shortcode-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/optimizing-the-youtube-shortcode-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>How to optimize the Youtube Shortcode for HugoThe Youtube embed shortcode for Hugo allows you to embed Youtube videos in your Hugo pages. Which is a pretty neat feature they provide to you out-of-the-box. The shortcode allows you to add two additional parameters that can be managed from the standard settings:
Unique Youtube video IDallowfullscreen (which you can set to “true”, which allows users to show the video in full screen mode)However, there are a ton of additional parameters you can include to customize your Youtube video embed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved my personal blog from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/why-i-moved-my-personal-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvv.github.io/personal_blog/why-i-moved-my-personal-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Why I moved my personal blog from Wordpress to HugoIt was one of those rare moments in my freelance career when I had some extra time on my hands. Eager to work on a website and tinker with some code. I was looking at my personal website (which you’re on right now). It was still built on Wordpress, with a basic theme and some useful features. In reality, I wasn’t using much of the power that Wordpress holds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
