<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data governance on Martijn van Vreeden</title>
    <link>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/tags/data-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data governance on Martijn van Vreeden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/tags/data-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Composable CDP&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/understanding-composable-cdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/understanding-composable-cdp/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Composable CDP’s One of the new hot topics in tech is the “Composable CDP.” Databricks is sharing a good definition of a Composable CDP in their article written together with Hightouch and Snowplow Analytics.
“A Composable CDP consists of the same components as their off-the-shelf counterparts; Data Collection, Data Storage and Modeling, and Data Activation. By implementing a best-in-class product at each layer of the Composable CDP, organizations can achieve a far more extensible CDP solution that can solve problems well beyond the common use cases of off-the-shelf CDPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create Google Tag Manager documentation with R</title>
      <link>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/create-google-tag-manager-documentation-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/create-google-tag-manager-documentation-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Create Google Tag Manager documentation with RCreating digital data documentation can be a painstaking, boring, but extremely useful endeavor. Knowing what digital data is available to you and others can be helpful to understand the potential of your data set, as well as provide context to analysis, reporting and other ways to leverage data.
To take some of the effort out of creating documentation about the contents of your Google Tag Manager account, I have created a script that pulls data out of the environment and outputs a simple Excel file, which you can share with stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
