<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Martijn van Vreeden</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Martijn van Vreeden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Google Consent Management</title>
      <link>/updates-to-google-consent-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates-to-google-consent-management/</guid>
      <description>Updates to Google Consent Management In March 2024, a new European privacy regulation will be implemented. This will have an impact on how we collect and process data.
Why is this important?
A new European regulation (Digital Markets Act) requires big tech to protect its users. They are responsible for respecting and collecting user consent As a result, we need to update our way of collecting data in GTM to &amp;ldquo;Consent Mode v2&amp;rdquo; All Google Advertising tracking will go through GA4 Consent Management will look different in GTM, as a result of the update If we don&amp;rsquo;t use this new technique, we cannot effectively use Google advertising products, starting march 2024 Coincidentally, Google Chrome will stop accepting 3rd party cookies end of March 2024 too, which means the urgency to shift is even higher What do we need to do to migrate?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Composable CDP&#39;s</title>
      <link>/understanding-composable-cdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/understanding-composable-cdp/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Composable CDP’s One of the new hot topics in tech is the “Composable CDP.” Databricks is sharing a good definition of a Composable CDP in their article written together with Hightouch and Snowplow Analytics.
“A Composable CDP consists of the same components as their off-the-shelf counterparts; Data Collection, Data Storage and Modeling, and Data Activation. By implementing a best-in-class product at each layer of the Composable CDP, organizations can achieve a far more extensible CDP solution that can solve problems well beyond the common use cases of off-the-shelf CDPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s happening in Digital Analytics</title>
      <link>/what-is-happening-in-digital-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-is-happening-in-digital-analytics/</guid>
      <description>What’s happening in Digital Analytics in 2023When you go online or to conferences you can find a ton of resources about Digital Analytics. The vast majority of content seems to be related to marketing technology. The transition from Google Universal Analytics to Google Analytics 4 is an instigator for martech providers and consultants to focus on technology in digital analytics.
I appreciate the value of collecting quality data in a technical solution for analysis and configuring tools to get the most out of them, but don’t be fooled, there’s more going on in the digital analytics space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager Server-side</title>
      <link>/google-tag-manager-server-side-advantages-and-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/google-tag-manager-server-side-advantages-and-concerns/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager Server-sideGoogle Tag Manager server-side is a way of running Google Tag Manager on a server instead of in the browser (client-side). It can potentially have a huge impact on the way you collect data for the user. This article is not going to be a how-to guide to using Google Tag Manager server-side. Instead, it will be an outline of some of the most important advantages and concerns related to this new product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding retention with customer feedback data</title>
      <link>/understanding-retention-with-customer-feedback-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/understanding-retention-with-customer-feedback-data/</guid>
      <description>Understanding retention with customer feedback dataTo get a better understanding of customer behavior in relation to the quality of the product and services a company provides, we often use customer feedback forms. We all know the concepts of NPS, CES or other ways of getting an understanding of customer satisfaction. What are the biggest differences and which one predicts retention most reliably? Let’s find out.
To get started, let’s run by the most popular methods available to measure customer satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add Google Tag Manager to Hugo static website</title>
      <link>/how-to-add-google-tag-manager-to-hugo-static-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-add-google-tag-manager-to-hugo-static-website/</guid>
      <description>How to add Google Tag Manager to a Hugo static websiteIn this article I will provide a step-by-step instruction and code samples on how to implement Google Tag Manager and a datalayer to your Hugo static website. As a digital analytics consultant I can appreciate the value a good Google Tag Manager (GTM) implementation can have for your business or even to optimize your user’s blog experience.
How to add the standard Google Tag Manager container to a Hugo websiteTo make sure that Google Tag Manager is enabled, we will have to include the Google Tag Manager container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things you need to know about the new Google Analytics 4</title>
      <link>/10-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-google-app-web-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-google-app-web-analytics/</guid>
      <description>10 Things you need to know about the new Google Analytics 4On July 31st 2019, Google introduced a “new” analytics solution they called Google Analytics 4. Google Analytics 4 is Google’s answer to the changing digital landscape we are dealing with as analysts. Google Analytics 4 will replace the current Google Universal Analytics in the future.
In this article I will share 10 things you need to know about the new Google Analytics 4 tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo shortcode to serve images in next-gen formats</title>
      <link>/hugo-shortcode-to-serve-images-in-next-gen-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hugo-shortcode-to-serve-images-in-next-gen-formats/</guid>
      <description>Hugo shortcode to serve images in next-gen formatsIn my last blogpost I shared 10 ways to improve your Hugo website performance. My last tip was to serve images in next-gen formats. This could improve the performance of your website significantly. Eventhough there are multiple next-gen formats you can integrate, the best browser compatibility will come by using WebP, created by Google. Unfortunately, not all browsers support this format yet (looking at you, Safari!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways to improve your (Hugo) website performance</title>
      <link>/10-ways-to-improve-your-hugo-website-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10-ways-to-improve-your-hugo-website-performance/</guid>
      <description>10 Ways to improve your (Hugo) website performanceWebsite performance matters. Even if I would selfishly ignore all other human visitors to my website, I would be supporting Google’s mission to make the web faster and help myself climb the ranks of Google. In this article I describe 10 ways to make your Hugo website (or any other website) faster and give users a better experience.
These are the 10 tips I will be discussing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create Google Tag Manager documentation with R</title>
      <link>/create-google-tag-manager-documentation-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/create-google-tag-manager-documentation-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Create Google Tag Manager documentation with RCreating digital data documentation can be a painstaking, boring, but extremely useful endeavor. Knowing what digital data is available to you and others can be helpful to understand the potential of your data set, as well as provide context to analysis, reporting and other ways to leverage data.
To take some of the effort out of creating documentation about the contents of your Google Tag Manager account, I have created a script that pulls data out of the environment and outputs a simple Excel file, which you can share with stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Youtube Shortcode for Hugo</title>
      <link>/optimizing-the-youtube-shortcode-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/optimizing-the-youtube-shortcode-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>How to optimize the Youtube Shortcode for HugoThe Youtube embed shortcode for Hugo allows you to embed Youtube videos in your Hugo pages. Which is a pretty neat feature they provide to you out-of-the-box. The shortcode allows you to add two additional parameters that can be managed from the standard settings:
Unique Youtube video IDallowfullscreen (which you can set to “true”, which allows users to show the video in full screen mode)However, there are a ton of additional parameters you can include to customize your Youtube video embed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved my personal blog from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>/why-i-moved-my-personal-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-i-moved-my-personal-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Why I moved my personal blog from Wordpress to HugoIt was one of those rare moments in my freelance career when I had some extra time on my hands. Eager to work on a website and tinker with some code. I was looking at my personal website (which you’re on right now). It was still built on Wordpress, with a basic theme and some useful features. In reality, I wasn’t using much of the power that Wordpress holds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Spotify data with R</title>
      <link>/collecting-spotify-data-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collecting-spotify-data-with-r/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts to analyse the digital me.
Collecting Spotify data with RSpotify has made its data very accessible to endusers to play with. Their API provides you with a plethora of options to get to their data, which is a ton of fun to analyse.
To get started, you wil need to R packages to access the data and process it afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Google Analytics internal search data with R</title>
      <link>/visualising-google-analytics-internal-search-data-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/visualising-google-analytics-internal-search-data-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Visualising Google Analytics internal search data with RIt’s a well-known fact that for many content-rich websites like e-commerce website the internal search engine is one of the most important features to navigate the website to find the right product. Google Analytics has created several standard reports to show you how visitors use your internal search engine and how this impacts your KPI’s. These reports can be quite useful, but they may also limit your way of analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Google Location data with R</title>
      <link>/analysing-google-location-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analysing-google-location-data/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts to analyse the digital me.
Analyse Google Location data with RGoogle is happily tracking my every move, thanks to my Android Samsung phone and poor privacy setting skills. Google collects my data about my movement through their location tracker. A lot of data!
In this blog I will explore the location data Google has collected about me since 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualize and analyse IMDB ratings with R (part 2)</title>
      <link>/visualize-and-analyse-imdb-ratings-with-r-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/visualize-and-analyse-imdb-ratings-with-r-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Visualize and analyse IMDB ratings with R (part 2)This post is part of a series of posts to analyse the digital me.
In my previous post about analysing IMDB ratings in this series I explored some of the data I collected about my movie preferences, also compared to the ratings other IMDB raters.
In this post I will dig a little deeper to learn more about my own personal movie preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualize and analyse IMDB ratings with R</title>
      <link>/visualize-and-analyse-imdb-ratings-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/visualize-and-analyse-imdb-ratings-with-r/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts to analyze the digital me.
Visualize and analyse IMDB ratings with RIn my previous post in this series I shared how I collect and store my personal ratings data from IMDB and enrich it with a few important variables about the movie.
In this post I will explore the data to learn about my movie preferences. I will be using some R packages to structure the data properly and other packages to build plots:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting my IMDB ratings with R and Rvest</title>
      <link>/getting-my-imdb-ratings-with-r-and-rvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/getting-my-imdb-ratings-with-r-and-rvest/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts to analyse the digital me.
Getting my IMDB ratings with R and RvestI’m a big fan of IMDB and have been for many years. It is a fantastic website with a lot of information about movies, documentaries and tv-series. Besides fact-checking (“who was that guy playing in that one movie?”) it is also a place for me to collect all the ratings I have done on movies in the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the digital me | Martijn van Vreeden</title>
      <link>/meet-the-digital-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meet-the-digital-me/</guid>
      <description>Meet the digital meThis is likely the most self-centered blogpost you will read today, maybe even this year. Because this post is all about me, the digital me.
Just like all people these days, I leave a digital footprint. I use apps, digital services and websites to share my experiences with others, keep people posted of what I do and compare what I do with all the stuff other people do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
