<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>digital analytics on Martijn van Vreeden</title>
    <link>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/categories/digital-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in digital analytics on Martijn van Vreeden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/categories/digital-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s happening in Digital Analytics</title>
      <link>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/what-is-happening-in-digital-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/what-is-happening-in-digital-analytics/</guid>
      <description>What’s happening in Digital Analytics in 2023When you go online or to conferences you can find a ton of resources about Digital Analytics. The vast majority of content seems to be related to marketing technology. The transition from Google Universal Analytics to Google Analytics 4 is an instigator for martech providers and consultants to focus on technology in digital analytics.
I appreciate the value of collecting quality data in a technical solution for analysis and configuring tools to get the most out of them, but don’t be fooled, there’s more going on in the digital analytics space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding retention with customer feedback data</title>
      <link>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/understanding-retention-with-customer-feedback-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martijnvanvreeden.nl/understanding-retention-with-customer-feedback-data/</guid>
      <description>Understanding retention with customer feedback dataTo get a better understanding of customer behavior in relation to the quality of the product and services a company provides, we often use customer feedback forms. We all know the concepts of NPS, CES or other ways of getting an understanding of customer satisfaction. What are the biggest differences and which one predicts retention most reliably? Let’s find out.
To get started, let’s run by the most popular methods available to measure customer satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
